exoticindiaart.com 2015-06-16

# Indian Jewelry - Indian Artwork Buddha Statues & Hindu Books | Exotic India Art

Indian Arts and Crafts LLC dba Exotic India has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for our website: www.exoticindiaart.com

Indian Arts and Crafts LLC has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy statement and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Web site, www.exoticindiaart.com. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact Dr. S. K. Verma at privacy@exoticindiaart.com. If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request).

##  ** _Registration_**

In order to use this Web site, we request certain personally identifiable information from you on the registration form. During registration you are required to give contact information (such as name and email address). We use this information to contact you about the services on our site in which you have expressed interest.

 _Orders_

If you purchase a product or service from us, we request certain personally identifiable information from you on our order form. You must provide contact information (such as name, email, and shipping address) and financial information (such as credit card number, expiration date).

We use this information for billing purposes and to fill your orders. If we have trouble processing an order, we will use this information to contact you.

##  **Affiliate Program**

If you choose to sign up for our affiliate program we will ask for your name, email address, address and a referring URL. We collect this information in order to complete the process of signing you up for our affiliate program.

Affiliates can update their information in our records by signing-in to their account at http://www.exoticindiaart.com/affiliate_program.php3

###  **Newsletters**

If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter, we will use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you. Out of respect for your privacy, we provide you a way to unsubscribe. Please see the “Choice and Opt-out” section.

###  **Links to Other Sites**

If you click on a link to a third party site, including on an advertisement, you will leave the www.exoticindiaart.com site you are visiting and go to the site you selected. Because we cannot control the activities of third parties, we cannot accept responsibility for any use of your personally identifiable information by such third parties, and we cannot guarantee that they will adhere to the same privacy practices as www.exoticindiaart.com. We encourage you to review the privacy statements of any other service provider from whom you request services. If you visit a third party website that is linked to an www.exoticindiaart.com site, you should read that site’s privacy statement before providing any personally identifiable information.

###  **Exoticindiaart.com does not share, sell, rent or trade your personal information with third parties other than as described within this privacy statement.**

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web site. If we are involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information

**Agents/Service Providers**  
We use other third parties such as a shipping company to fulfill orders, and a credit card processing company to bill you for goods and services, we will share (such as your shipping address, phone number, or email) as necessary for the third party to provide that service.

These third parties are prohibited from using your personally identifiable information for promotional purposes.

**Cookies**  
A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies on this site. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site.

We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time.

We set a persistent cookie to maintain items in your shopping cart, so you don’t have to build it more than once. Persistent cookies also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site.

If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some areas of our site, such as shopping cart, will be limited.

 _Third Party Cookies_

The use of cookies by third parties is not covered by our privacy statement. We do not have access or control over these cookies.

**Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs)**  
Third parties employ a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers’ personally identifiable information.

**Security**  
The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as credit card number and/or social security number, national ID, personal health information) on our registration or order forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personally identifiable information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can email us at **privacy@exoticindiaart.com**

**Choice/Opt-Out**  
Our site provides users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving newsletters from us at the point where we request information about the visitor.

This site gives users the following options for removing their information from our database to not receive future communications or to no longer receive our service.

  * You can send email to [unsubscribe@exoticindiaart.com](mailto:unsubscribe@exoticindiaart.com)
  * You can visit the following URL: <http://www.exoticindiaart.com/unsubscribe.php3>

**Correct/Update/Delete/Remove**  
If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, delete/remove or update it by making the change within the “My Account” section of the site once you have logged in or by emailing our Customer Support at [info@exoticindiaart.com](mailto:info@exoticindiaart.com). We will respond to your access request within 30 days.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer user your information to provide you services contact us at info@exoticindia.com. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.   
**Customer Testimonials/Comments**  
We post customer testimonials/comments on our web site which may contain personally identifiable information. We do obtain the customer's consent via email prior to posting the testimonial or comment to post their name along with their testimonial or comment. To request removal of your personal information from our testimonials or comments, contact us at [privacy@exoticindiaart.com](mailto:privacy@). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

**Tell-A-Friend and e-Cards**  
If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend or choose to send your friend an e-card, we will ask you for your friend’s name and email address. We will automatically send your friend an email inviting him or her to visit the site or an e-card if you chose to utilize this feature. Exoticindiaart.com stores this information for the purpose of sending this email and tracking the success of our referral program.

Your friend may contact us at unsubscribe@exoticindiaart.com to request that we remove this information from our database.

**Social Media (Features) and Widgets**  
Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook recommend button, Google+ recommend button, and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy statement of the company providing it.

**Single Sign-On**  
You can log in to our site using sign-in services such as Facebook Connect or an Open ID provider. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form. Services like Facebook Connect give you the option to post information about your activities on this Web site to your profile page to share with others within your network.

**Gift Voucher**  
If you purchase a gift voucher from us we will collect the recipient’s name, email address and the gift voucher value. Once you purchase the voucher we will send your friend a one time email that contains their gift voucher. We store their information for the purpose of tracking the success of the gift voucher program and to ensure that the gift voucher has been delivered. Your friend may contact us at unsubscribe@exoticindiaart.com to request that we remove this information from our database.

**Changes in this Privacy Statement**  
If we decide to change our privacy statement, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the home page, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this statement, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page prior to the change becoming effective.

**Contacting the Web Site**  
If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact:

Kapil Goel Exotic India Art Pvt Ltd. 63 Model Basti New Delhi 110005 **Tel:** +91-11-4247 3015; 2737 3485

Last Updated on December 30, 2013
